# **Daniel Legan**

Software Engineer | 952.693.3325 | <a href="mailto:legan14daniel@gmail.com">legan14daniel@gmail.com</a> | <a href="mailto:github.com/Daniel-Legan">github.com/Daniel-Legan</a>

# **ABOUT**

I've always had the desire to build new things. Whether it be computers, bikes, or apps, I use my precision mindset into creating the best. I have experience building dynamic web applications in JavaScript, HTML, and CSS. Additionally, I enjoy pair programming, problem solving, using console logs, and reading errors to find the source of the bug. Software development interlinks my two passions of art and technology, allowing me to make interactive websites with modern design elements.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- JavaScript
- jQuery
- C
- SQL
- HTML
- CSS

- Material-UI
- React
- Node
- Redux
- Express
- Redux-Saga

- .NET
- Postico
- Postman
- APIs
- Visual Studio Code
- GitHub

## **EDUCATION**

### Prime Digital Academy | January 2023

Full Stack Software Engineering Certification

• An intensive 1000+ full immersive experience that teaches modern technologies such as JavaScript, React, Node, Express, and SQL. Additional training in public speaking and presentation practice, professional skill development, diversity, equity, and inclusion, and real-world client work.

### Normandale Community College | June 2021 - May 2022

Courses taken in Discrete Structures, Calculus, Introduction to Programming, and Programming in C.
Received 4.0 GPA.

#### University of Minnesota | December 2014

**B.S.** in Clinical Laboratory Sciences

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Prime Digital Academy | August 2022 - January 2023

Full-Stack Software Development Student

#### **Solo Project: Noob to Master**

- Developed an app to help "noobs" of a particular video game connect with a "master" of the game. Application used Google Maps API/AutoComplete for noob users to find master users on a map and convert their address into latitude and longitude coordinates.
- Technologies used: JavaScript, React, Material-UI, SQL, Redux-Saga, Node, Express, Google Maps API

### **Group Project: Faceless Pro**

- Faceless Pro is an early stage startup looking to reduce the bias when job searching and hiring.
- Collaborated with our client and a team of developers to develop a blind recruitment job board that levels the playing field for all by taking name, age, gender, and race out of the equation.
- Technologies used: JavaScript, React, Material-UI, SQL, Redux-Saga, Node, Express, Multer

## Regions Hospital | February 2021 - September 2022

### Medical Technologist

- Performed quality control to ensure accurate reporting of test results by reviewing Levey-Jennings plots.
- Frequent communication with doctors, nurses, and other technologists from diverse backgrounds.
- Involved in emergency situations that require quick decision making to ensure good patient outcomes.

# Mayo Clinic | May 2015 - November 2020

## Medical Technologist

- Performed instrument maintenance and quality control on a wide variety of analyzers.
- Interacted with a diverse population of patients by performing venous punctures.
- Assigned to train and mentor other technologists to ensure compliance with industry regulations.
- Created new documentation to assist with record keeping and maintenance to ensure compliance.
- Remained adaptable, providing backup relief for the technical specialist as needed.